# Joannne Aluka

#### FRONT-END SOFTWARE ENGINEER

### Summary

I am a Front-End Software Engineer with **3 years** of experience in designing & building both web and mobile applications. My expertise as a software engineer is multi-faceted with a keen focus on front-end web development with **React** and **Typescript**. I've also worked on a variety of cross-platform mobile apps built with **React Native**.

I have a deep passion for my work, fueled by the desire to solve problems and create value. I am a self-motivated and self-driven individual who is always looking for new challenges and opportunities to grow and improve.

## **Portfolio & Projects**

Github Account: https://github.com/joannealuka

Personal Website (Portfolio): https://joannealuka.myportfolio.com

Linked-In: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joan-aluka/

# Work experience

### **Full Stack Developer**

A-Trader

Jan 2023 - Current Position

May 2021 - December 2022

- Wrote technical documentation for new features, architectural designs, and cheat sheets for developers and the QA team.
- Designed and built new onboarding processes that reduced the amount of information captured while maintaining our KYC obligations. The data was used to pre-populate the e-lease document to avoid data entry again.
- Peer-reviewed code to improve quality and catch bugs before moving to QA. It reduced the number of tasks sent back by 30%.
- Created software workflows that improved developer experience by easing the pain of keeping the development environment up to date with staging.

#### Front-End Engineer

#### **Powwater**

- Developing front -end mobile and web architecture and Implementing UI and UX features on mobile or web based on user requirements.
- Designed and built a new ERP system that improved customer satisfaction by ensuring user experiences
  were easy and intuitive. The reduced time and money spent training staff on new software boosted our sales
  by 25%.
- Performed optimization across the software we provided, improving performance by up to 300% in some cases. I used caching (Redis/MemCache), lazing loading components, and optimized SQL queries, e.g fixing n+1 query select problems.
- Embedded into a customer's operations during the pilot phase of ERP deployment I got a first-hand view of how staff interacted with our software and made recommendations that were in line with real-world use cases which improved our testing processes.

#### Front-End Developer

#### **Oaknet Business**

### June 2020 - April 2021

- Collaborated in the development, delivery and support of software solutions including a Case Management System for the Office of the Director of Public Prosecutions and a Government Management System for Kajiado County
- Resolved code merging conflicts and streamlined update versioning of our software using git, for a fluid and parallel development within the team.
- Collaborated with backend developers to design the API, and to streamline the data requirement for fluent customer journeys on the frontend.

# **Education**

# Diploma in Information Technology

AkiraChix

# Technical Skills

- HTML5 & CSS
- Javascript(Node.js)
- React
- React Native
- Vue.js
- NextJS

- MySQL
- Typescripts
- Redux
- MongoD
- GraphQL

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Figma
- InDesign

2019